Now that you've got your ROS environment variables in place,
ROS 環境変数が落ち着いたので
you're ready to run some turtlesim nodes.
turtlesim ノードを実行できるようになりました
So let's jump right into this.
さっそく始めましょう
The first thing you're going to need to do is start the ROS master process.
最初にしなければならないことは ROS マスタープロセスを起動することですが
To do this, all you need to do is run the command roscore.
実際行うのはコマンド roscore の実行だけです
And there we go.
はい このとおり
We've been hit with a wall of text ending with the line 'started core service'.
テキストがずらっと並んで 「started core service」という行で終わっています
You don't need to worry about all the detail printed on
コンソールに出力された内容を気にする必要はありません
the console as none of it is really relevant to us right now.
ここではあまり関係ありませんから
As long as you don't see any colorful red text
赤くて目立つテキストがなければ大丈夫です エラーがあるという印です
disclaiming that there is an error, you're good to go.
問題ないので先へ進みましょう
Now that the master process is running,
マスタープロセスが稼働したので
you'll be able to run nodes.
ノードを実行できます
The first node that you're going to run is the turtlesim node itself.
実行する最初のノードは turtlesim ノード本体です
To run the node, you'll want to open a new terminal and execute the rosrun command.
ノードを実行するには 新しいターミナルを開いて rosrun コマンドを実行します
The first parameter you'll be passing to the rosrun command is turtlesim,
rosrun コマンドに渡す最初のパラメーターは turtlesim
the name of the ROS package containing the turtlesim nodes,
turtlesim ノードがある ROS パッケージの名前と
and turtlesim_node which is the name of
それから 実行したいパッケージに常駐している
the node executable residing in the package that you wish to run.
実行可能ノードの名前 ここは turtlesim_node です
And there you have it, you're running the simulator and
結果はこのとおり シミュレーターを実行すると
you've got a little turtle waiting to be commanded around the window.
小さなカメがウィンドウ内でコマンドを待っています
To command the turtle to move,
コマンドでカメを動かすには
you must run another node,
別のノード turtle_teleop ノードを
the turtle teleop node.
実行する必要があります
Once again, you'll need to open another terminal window.
繰り返しですが 別のターミナルウィンドウを開きます
And you'll run the same command you ran a moment ago
ここで先ほどと同じコマンドを実行しますが 実行可能ノードの名前が違います
with the exception of the node executable name; rosrun turtlesim, our package name,
rosrun turtlesim パッケージ名 次が turtle_teleop_key
and turtle_teleop_key, the name of the node executable you wish to run.
ここが実行したいノードの名前になります
If you ever forget the name of the package or node that you
パッケージやノードの名前が思い出せない場合は
wish to run tab completion can be helpful.
タブ完了の実行が役に立ちます
So, let me go ahead and backspace.
では 先へ進めましょう ここは削除します
Let's say I don't know the node name,
ノード名がわからないとしましょう
but I know that it starts with turtle,
でも turtle で始まっていたことは覚えています
and then I hit tab tab.
このときは Tab キーを 2 回押します
I see that the turtlesim package has
turtlesim パッケージには turtle という語で
two nodes that start with the word turtle: There's turtlesim_node,
始まるノードが 2 つありましたturtlesim_node は
the node that we just ran,
今実行したばかりのノードです
and then there's turtle teleop key,
turtle_teleop_key は
the node that we're trying to run.
これから実行しようとしているノードです
So rosrun turtlesim, turtle teleop key.
そのためここは rosrun turtlesim turtle_teleop_key になります
Now the turtlesim teleop node is running.
さて turtlesim_teleop ノードが稼働しました
With the turtle teleop console selected,
turtle_teleop のコンソールを選択していると
you can use the arrow keys to drive the turtle around the virtual world.
矢印キーを使用して仮想世界でカメを動かせます
Let's give this a try.
試してみましょう
Yep. And there we go.
おっとこんな感じです
We're now ready to begin investigating the turtlesim coms.
さて 次はタートルシムのコマンドを調べてみましょう